喂 - 莉斯贝丝·萨兰德
- Hello? - Lisbeth Salander?
这是缓刑部门
It's the probation department.
我打电话来是想告诉你你有了新监护人
I'm calling to tell you you've got a new guardian.
你再也不能联系我了
You can never contact me again.
如果你这么做了 我会把这部电影的拷贝寄给警方和媒体
If you do, I'll send copies of the film to the police and the press.
明白了吗
You got it?
丽斯贝丝 你是个职业黑客
Lisbeth, you work as a professional hacker.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
- 嗨 妈妈 - 你是丽斯贝丝吗
- Hi, Mum. - Are you Lisbeth?
你有男朋友吗?
Do you have a boyfriend?
有个人 但最好不要坠入爱河
There's someone... but it's best not to fall in love.
你比谁都清楚这一点
You know that better than anyone.
我应该给你选一个更好的父亲
I should have picked a better father for you.
你都经历了些什么 你怎么会变成这样
What have you been through? How did you get like this?
你救了我一命
You saved my life.
你对我了如指掌 而我对你一无所知
You know everything about me, and I don't know shit about you.
事情就是这样
That's how it is.
我希望你一切都好 打电话给我
I hope yourre all right. Call me.
干杯!
Cheers!
似乎从开曼群岛的一个账户中提取了一大笔钱
...It appeared that a large sum has been withdrawn from an account in the Cayman Islands.
丽斯贝丝
Lisbeth.
玩火的女孩
THE GIRL WHO PLAYED WITH FIRE
第三部份
PART 3
桑德斯特伦
Sandström!
- 我们给你找了另一份工作 - 我不认为 是的 我们有
- We've got another job for you. - I don't think... Yes... We do.
- 你还在和她约会吗 - 谁
- Are you still seeing her? - Who?
- 莉斯贝丝·萨兰德 - 不 我有一年没见过她了
- Lisbeth Salander. - No, I haven't seen her for a year.
- 为什么 - 我不知道为什么
- How come? - I don't know why.
怎么了 发生什么事了吗
wWwhat, did something happen?
如果我们有争执的话
If we had an argument?
有一天一切都很好 然后她就不接我的电话了
One day werre fine, then she stops taking my calls.
真奇怪
Strange.
我们最好快跑 达格·斯文森将参加今天的会议
Wer'd better run. Dag Svensson will be coming to the meeting today.
就是那个有贩卖记录的人 东欧女孩
The guy with that trafficking story. The Eastern European girls.
- 那么 这家伙是谁 - 自由职业者 年轻 有抱负
- So, who is this guy? - Freelancer, young, ambitious.
- 状态良好 - 状态良好吗
- In good shape. - In good shape?
- 你研究它多久了 - 大约四年
- How long have you worked on it? - About four years.
我的女朋友米娅·伯格曼让我谈到了这个话题
My girlfriend, Mia Bergman, got me onto the subject.
她是做性别研究的犯罪学家
She's a criminologist doing gender studies.
- 她的博士论文是关于人口贩运的 - 这么说你们是一个团队了
- Her PhD thesis is about trafficking. - S0 you're a team?
不 米娅专注于女孩 而我专注于供应商和客户基础
No, Mia focuses on the girls, while I concentrate on the suppliers and the client base.
- 你有什么 - 重要客户的证据
- What have you got? - Proof of prominent clients.
其中一人是司法部的一名成员 他帮助起草了性交易法律
One is a member of the justice department who helped draft the sex trade laws.
三名警察：一名来自缉毒组 一名来自安全警察
Three policemen: one from Vice, one from the security police.
这里 五名律师 一名法官和一名检察官
Here. Five lawyers, a judge and a DA.
这些女孩的地位如此之低 以至于被法律系统忽视
These girls have so little status they're ignored by the legal system.
所以它就这么继续下去了
So it just carries on?
不幸的是 我的结论是…… 法律系统不想碰它
My conclusion, unfortunately, is that... ...the legal system doesn't want to touch it.
虐待东欧十几岁的女孩不是优先事项
The abuse of teenage girls from Eastern Europe is not a priority.
妓女就是妓女 只是系统的一部分
A whore is a whore. Just part of the system.
- 你查到什么了 - 研究已经完成了
- How far have you got? - The research is complete.
剩下的就是事实核查和与赌徒对峙
what's left is fact - checking and confronting the punters.
等一等
Hold on.
粗心大意的事实核查让我坐了三个月的牢
Careless fact - checking earned me three months in prison.
我们指认的任何人都有机会发表评论
Anyone we finger gets a chance to comment.
绝对一点儿没错 别担心 我的文件是无懈可击的
Absolutely. Don't worry, my documentation is watertight.
我觉得这听起来很棒
think it sounds great.
是啊
Yep.
好的 我们付的钱不多
OK. We don't pay much.
但我们可以给你提供两个月的合同
But we can offer you a two - month contract.
我们会在这里给你弄张桌子
And we'll get you a desk here.
- 听起来不错 - 听起来不错
- Sound good? - It sounds great.
我肯定会踩到几个脚趾 但
wWe!'ll be stepping on a few toes, that's for sure, but...
这就是千禧年的全部意义 对吗 这就是我们要做的
...that's the whole point of Millennium, right? It's what we do.
- 欢迎来到千禧年 达格 - 谢谢你
- Welcome to Millennium, Dag. - Thank you.
- 现在你可以放松了 - 谢谢
- Now you can relax. - Thanks.
谢谢
Thank you.
卧室在那里 主卧套房在左边 我马上就来
The bedroom's there. The master suite is on the left. III be right with you.
我能为您做点什么
Can I help you?
我在找一套可以俯瞰水景的公寓
I'm after a flat overlooking the water.
- 我不认为这是给你的 - 没有 为什么不行
- I don't think this one is for you. - No? Why not?
要买这套公寓 你需要很多零用钱
To buy this apartment, you need a lot of pocket money.
真的
Really?
比尔伯格地产公司 我是Joakim Persson
Billberg Properties, Joakim Persson speaking.
- 怎么样 - 很好 太棒了
- How's it going? - Good. Great.
S0 - S0 我正在试着联系其中一个赌徒 保安警察 一辆冈纳比约克
S0 - so0. I'm trying to get hold of one of those punters, the Security Police guy, a Gunnar Björck.
就像他消失得无影无踪
It's like he's vanished into thin air.
你查到什么了
what have you got?
邮局信箱地址
A post office box address.
- 一个邮政信箱地址 - 是的
- A post office box address? - Yes.
- 试试抽奖的把戏 - 什么
- Try the lottery trick. - What?
彩票骗局 你发一封信说他赢了 一部带有GPS的超豪华手机
The lottery trick. You send a letter saying he's won... a super - deluxe phone with GPS.
他是二十个有机会赢得十万美元奖金的人之一
And that he's one of twenty with a chance to win a hundred grand
如果他参加市场调查的话 彩票骗局
if he takes part in a market survey. The lottery trick.
正确的 这合法吗
Right. Is it legal?
赠送手机并不违法
It's hardly illegal to give away a phone.
告诉他们你是Indigo市场研究公司的 我一直都是这样
Tell them you're with Indigo Marketing Research. I always do.
- 那是297克朗 - 谢谢 不用找钱了
- That'll be 297 kronor. - Thanks. Keep the change.
- 你是不是有点宿醉了 - 没有
- Are you allittle hung over? - NO.
好的 赶快
Sure. Come on.
- 你对达格有什么意见 - 没什么某物 我不知道
- What have you got against Dag? - Nothing. Something. I don't know.
你觉得他太年轻了 不是吗
You think he's a bit young, don't you?
他是我喜欢的那种记者 直截了当地说出事情的核心
He's the kind of journalist I like. Gets right to the heart of things.
就像你一样 这就是你不喜欢他的原因 他太像了
Just like you. That's why you don't like him. He's too similar.
贩运、有组织犯罪和社会的反应 米娅·伯格曼著
Trafficking, Organised Crime and Society's Response by Mia Bergman.
是
Yes.
这就对了
There you go.
这是对伊恩·弗莱明的经典著作《007》的讽刺
It's an ironic allusion to lan Fleming's classic 007 book.
请参见
see.
詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.
S：它是如何运作的
Söo how does it work?
他们经常以规模较小、相当混乱的帮派运作
They often operate in small, rather muddled gangs.
请自便
Please help yourselves.
普通帮派只有几个成员
The average gang has only a few members.
一半是俄罗斯人或波罗的海人 一半是瑞典人
Half Russians or Balts, half Swedes.
女孩们被带到了郊区
The girls are taken to a suburb.
问题是 一旦他们 一旦他们到了瑞典 他们就别无选择
The thing is, once they've... Once they're in Sweden, they have no choice.
她要么顺从 要么被皮条客虐待或折磨
Either she goes along with it, or she's abused or tortured by her pimp.
他们可以逃走 因为这些帮派做的第一件事就是拿走他们的护照
They cantt flee, as the very first thing these gangs do is take their passports away.
你有黑帮头目的名字吗
Have you got any names of the gang leaders?
不是的
No.
我不能肯定地说
Not that I can confirm with any certainty.
这些行动的领导人都是出了名的暴力分子
The leaders of these kinds of operation are notoriously violent men.
这其中有一个明确的权位顺序 没有人敢说话 尤其是所有的女孩
There's a clear pecking order. No one dares to talk, least of all the girls.
我想我们应该来点甜酒
I thought we'd have some dessert wine.
- 哦 对不起 - 这是我的错
- Oh, sorry. - It was my fault.
但从法律的角度来看 他对此了解多少
...but the legal angle, what does he know about that?
必须明确的是 贩运是一种侵犯人权的罪行
It must be made clear that trafficking is a crime against human rights.
他们应该像战犯一样被点名和羞辱 对吗
They should be named and shamed like war criminals. Right?
对吗 - 是的是
- Right? - Yes. Yes.
你今晚有什么特别的事吗
Are you doing anything special this evening?
去哪里
wWhere to?
- 去他的地方 - 贝尔曼斯加坦
- To his place. - Bellmansgatan.
保持联系
GET IN TOUCH!
您确定要删除该消息吗
ARE YOU SURE YOU WANT TO DELETE THE MESSAGE?
欢迎光临比约曼法律服务公司
WELCOME TO BJURMAN'S LEGAL SERVICES
- 比约曼先生 律师 - 什么事
- Mr Bjurman, the lawyer? - Yes?
这是一份1993年的警方报告 莉斯贝丝·萨兰德
This concerns a police report from 1993, Lisbeth Salander.
我的委托人想看一看
My client would like to have a look at it.
真的 你的客户是谁
Really? And who is your client?
- 我把文件放在乡下的家里 - 有复印件吗
- I keep the files at my country home. - Any copies?
不是的
No.
- 她还在国外吗 - 很有可能
- Is she still abroad? - Most likely.
谢谢
Thanks.
比约曼
Bjurman.
我会保持联系的
I'll be in touch.
评估报告
ASSESSMENT REPORT
你应该每月交一份关于我的报告
You're supposed to send in monthly reports about me.
- 我知道 - 不是每个月
- I do. - Not every month!
- 我没有把我所有的记录都保存在这里 - 闭嘴
- I don't keep all my records here. - Shut up!
定期提交积极的报告 我就不会打扰你了
Send in regular, positive reports, and I'll leave you alone.
搞砸了 我会把我们的小胶片送到全国每家报纸上
Mess up, and I'll send our little film to every paper in the country.
如果我死了 这部电影就会公之于众
If I die, the film will be made public.
如果你再碰我 我就杀了你
If you ever touch me again, III kill you.
最后一件事
One last thing.
如果你踏进那家法国诊所 想把你的纹身去掉 我就在你额头上纹身
If you set foot in that French clinic and try to remove your tattoo, I'll tattoo your forehead.
- 我说清楚了吗 - 说清楚了
- Have I made myself clear? - Yes.
我和她分手去了巴黎 我父母住在那里 你知道的
I broke up with her and went to Paris. My parents live there, you know.
我在克利希附近的一家俱乐部工作 一家很酷的俱乐部
And I worked at this club near Clichy. A really cool club.
我申请了这里的法学院 但直到 我才知道我被录取了
I had applied to law school here, but I didn't know I'd been accepted until...
你想要我的公寓吗
Do you want my apartment?
什么 - 你想要我的公寓吗
- What? - Do you want my apartment?
- 你要搬家吗 - 我已经搬了
- Are you moving? - I already have.
我没钱 我负担不起 房租已经预付了一年 你想要吗
I've got no money, I can't afford... The rent's been paid a year in advance. Do you want it?
好的
OK.
- 有一个条件 - 当然
- There's one condition. - Of course.
这里仍然是我的合法住所 所以我的邮件会寄到这里
This is still my legal residence, so my mail will be sent here.
- 我要你来处理这件事 - 当然
- I want you to take care of it. - Sure.
- 你住在哪里 - 其他地方
- So where are you staying? - Somewhere else.
我能来参观一下吗
Can I come for a visit?
不是的 现在不行
No. Not now.
但如果你有冲动 你会他妈的停下来吗
But if you get the urge, you'll stop by for a fuck?
我很想去 但这不是合同的一部分
I'd love to, but it's not part of the contract.
- 你是认真的吗 - 是的
- Are you serious? - Yeah.
到这儿来
Come here.
嘿 我有东西要给你
Hey, I've got something for you.
- 给你 生日快乐 - 今天不是我的生日
- Here. Happy birthday. - It's not my birthday.
这是去年的
It's from last year.
如果你不打算改掉那个坏习惯 你不妨穿得时髦一点
If you aren't going to quit that nasty habit, you might as well do it in style.
你是唯一一个送我礼物的人
You're the only person who ever gives me presents.
- 嗨 亲爱的 对不起我来晚了 - 嗨
- Hi, honey. Sorry I'm late. - Hi.
- 这是什么 - 你看过这个吗
- What is it? - Have you seen this?
伊琳娜的身体被发现
IRINA'S BODY FOUND
- Irina Hammuijärvi - 她在你的论文里 对吗
- Irina Hammuijärvi. - She was in your thesis, right?
她只有17岁 我最近才和她聊过
She was only 17. I spoke to her just recently.
她告诉我 她想辞职 把自己的生活理顺
She told me she wanted to quit and sort her life out.
然后就会发生这样的事
Then this happens.
是
Yes.
- 谁带她来的 - 她叫扎拉的人
- Who brought her here? - Someone she called Zala.
她很怕他 我还没能确认他的身份
She was terrified of him. I haven't managed to identify him.
- 我在论文中叫他安东 - 太奇怪了
- I've called him Anton in my thesis. - That's weird.
上周 我与一位广告记者Per - äke Sandström进行了对峙
I confronted an advertising journalist last week, Per - Åke Sandström.
他是个赌徒 他还提到了扎拉这个名字
He's a punter, and he also mentioned the name Zala.
- 你能猜出他的工作吗 - 不能
- Can you guess what his job was? - NO.
Per - äke Sandström为信息包做了布局
Per - Åke Sandström did the layout for an information pack
公共卫生研究所的性传播疾病
on sexually transmitted diseases for the Public Health Institute.
- 当我提到那两个女孩时 他的脸 - 够了 达格
- His face when I mentioned the girls... - That's enough, Dag!
对不起 宝贝
I'm sorry. Baby...
食物怎么样 好吃吗 非常好 安妮卡
How was the food? Was it good? It was very good, Annika.
- 我做的菜 - 很好吃 安妮卡
- I did the cooking! - It's delicious, Annika.
迈克 你为什么还是个单身汉
Mikael, why are you still a bachelor?
安吉丽娜阿姨 请 他不想 真的 但他是个如此英俊的男孩
Auntie Angelina, please. He doesn't want to... Really? But he's such a handsome boy.
- 你没有女人吗 - 不 我有
- Don't you have a woman? - Yes, I do.
- 很好 - 那就娶她吧
- Good. - Then marry her!
我会的 但她已经结婚了
I would, but she's already married.
Hil现在不是时候吗
Hil Is it a bad time?
不 我在我姐姐家和她的姻亲在一起
No, I'm at my sister's with a platoon of her in - laws.
听着 我只有几张照片的复印件
Listen, all I have is hard copies of the pictures.
米娅和我明天要走了 所以我想知道
Mia and I are going away tomorrow, so I was wondering...
- 我敢派快递员送他们吗 - 不 别那么做
- Do I dare send them with a courier? - No, don't do that.
我马上就要走了 我会顺道过去的
I'll be leaving soon. I'll drop by.
太棒了 最后一件事
Great. One last thing.
我需要一个叫扎拉的黑帮成员的信息
I need information on a gangster called Zala.
你不能在离出版这么近的地方添加新材料
You can't add new material this close to publication.
我知道 但我有预感这会有回报的
I know, but I have a feeling it might pay off.
- 我们晚点再讨论这个 - 当然…… - 我可以带你去别的地方 - 安妮卡 是?
- Let's discuss this later. - Sure... - I can give you a lift somewhere. - Annika... Yes?
- 我需要用一下你的律师技能 - 好的
- I need to use your lawyer skills. - OK.
我在处理一个贩卖人口的问题 在我们印刷之前 你能看一看吗
I'm working on a trafficking issue. Can you have a look before we go to print?
- 我不支持新闻自由 - 不 但有针对妇女的暴力行为
- I don't work with press freedoms. - No, but with violence against women.
没错
True.
两分钟
Two minutes.
发生什么事了吗 - 听起来像是枪声
- Has something happened? - It sounded like a gunshot.
- 枪声 - 就在刚才
- Gunshot? - Just now.
达格
Dag?
你好?
Hello?
- 你报了警 对吗 - 是的
- You called the police, right? - Yes.
好的 你看到发生了什么吗
OK. Did you see what happened?
不是的 我刚找到他们
No. I just found them.
大概十分钟后…… - 你看到可能的嫌疑犯了吗 - 没有
Something like ten minutes after... - Did you see a possible suspect? - NO.
- 也许是邻居们干的 - 好的
- Maybe the neighbours did. - OK.
你住在这里吗
Do you live here?
不 李 来这里看他们
No, LI...  came here to see them.
好的
OK.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
你好 布隆维斯特 你能回答几个问题吗
Hello, Blomkvist! Can you answer some questions?
这是不允许的
That's not allowed!
受害者是一名记者和一名犯罪学家
The victims were a journalist and a criminologist.
他们是由另一名记者发现的 千禧年的Mikael Blomkvist
They were found by another journalist, Millennium's Mikael Blomkvist.
因温纳斯特伦丑闻而闻名
Famous for the Wennerström scandal.
- 动机是什么 - 我们知道的不多
- What's the motive? - We don't know much.
那个女孩刚刚完成了她的论文
The girl had just completed her thesis.
我们将把这个案子放在最优先的位置 组织一支队伍
We!ll put top priority on this case. Put a team together.
- 汉斯·法斯特 杰克·霍姆伯格 - 索尼娅·莫迪格
- Hans Faste, Jerker Holmberg. - Sonja Modig.
好的 布布兰斯基 选择你的团队 但要开始行动起来
OK, Bublanski. Choose your team, but get cracking.
我是地区检察官埃克斯特伦
District Attorney Ekström speaking.
我们必须讨论两件事
We have to discuss two things.
我们应该发表达格的材料吗
Should we publish Dag's material?
我们能出版吗 米克和我刚刚讨论过这件事
Can we publish it? Micke and I have just been discussing this.
我们不知道他们为什么会被谋杀 可能是私人恩怨 一个神经病
We don't know why they were murdered. It could be personal. A psycho.
但我们不能排除与工作有关的可能性
But we can't rule out that it's work - related.
但是 迈克 你将这些谋杀描述为处决
But, Micke... You describe the murders as executions.
名单上的谁有能力做到这一点 然后逍遥法外呢
who on the list is capable of that? And getting away with it?
我们即将公布这些名字
Wer're on the verge of publishing the names
那些绝对不想要这种关注的人
of people who definitely don't want this kind of attention.
达格已经和他们中的一些人对质了
And Dag had already confronted some of them.
这纯属猜测
This is pure speculation.
警方不是应该有这份名单吗
Shouldn't the police have this list?
是 我们也许应该 不是的
Yes. We probably should... No.
我们可以公布一些赌客的名字 但不能透露我们的消息来源
We could release the names of a few punters, but we can't reveal our sources.
这可能会危及米娅为毕业论文采访的女孩的生命
It might endanger the lives of the girls Mia interviewed for her thesis.
对他们来说 这可能是生死攸关的问题
It may be a matter of life and death for them.
回到我的第一个问题 我们要出版吗
Back to my first question, do we publish?
就我个人而言 我觉得达格会希望我们这么做
Personally,  think Dag would want us to.
我想我们应该
I think we should.
克里斯特
Christer?
那好吧
All right, then.
双重杀戮 - 年轻夫妇被枪杀
DOUBLE KILLING - YOUNG COUPLE SHOT
你好 阿曼斯基
Hello, Armansky.
我可以进来吗
May I come in?
已经一年多了
It's been over a year.
- 你生气了吗 - 没有
- Are you angry? - NO.
你怎么在这儿 你需要一份工作吗
why are you here? Do you need a job?
你在别的地方工作吗
Do you work somewhere else?
我一直在旅行 我刚回来
I've been travelling. I just got back.
- 你去哪里了 - 到处都是 澳大利亚、新西兰
- Where'd you go? - Everywhere. Australia, New Zealand.
最近 我在加勒比海度过了一段时间
Most recently, I spent time in the Caribbean.
- 我不知道我为什么不说再见 - 你不在乎其他人
- I don't know why I didn't say goodbye. - You don't care about other people.
你把你的朋友当垃圾对待 就这么简单
You treat your friends like dirt, it's as simple as that.
布隆维斯特一直在试图联系你
Blomkvist's been trying to get hold of you.
他每个月至少打一次电话 看看你有没有联系
He calls at least once a month to see if you've been in touch.
他也很在乎 霍尔格·帕姆格伦也是如此
He cares, too. And so does Holger Palmgren.
他中风已经两年了 你还没有联系过他
It's been two years since his stroke, and you haven't contacted him.
他还活着
He's alive?
你甚至不知道他是死是活
You don't even know if he's dead or alive?
你一直在 不见了
You've been... gone.
我去过国外 我不得不离开一段时间
I've been abroad. I had to get away for a while.
- 你担心吗 - 没有
- Were you worried? - NO.
你是不可战胜的
Yourre invincible.
阿曼斯基很担心
Armansky was worried.
进展如何 带着你的新 守护者 比约曼
How's it going... with your new... guardian... Bjurman?
他很好 没关系的
He's OK. It's OK.
那你的 宣布不称职
what about your... declaration of incompetency?
我会处理好的 这不再是你的责任了
I'l take care of it. It's not your responsibility anymore.
不 我太老了 太老了
No, I'm too old. Too old.
一个愚蠢的老头
A stupid old man.
是啊 当你说这种话的时候
Yeah, when you say stuff like that.
嘿 关于那把枪的初步报告刚出来
Hey. A preliminary report just came in about the gun.
- 不合法 - 不 完全合法
- Ilegal? - No, totally legit.
它属于一位律师 尼尔斯·埃里克·比约曼 早在1983年购买的
It belongs to a lawyer. Nils Erik Bjurman. Purchased back in 1983.
- 店主住在斯德哥尔摩 - 真的
- The owner lives here in Stockholm. - Really?
我们设法提取了两个指纹 一个右拇指和一个食指
We managed to lift two prints, a right thumb and an index finger.
它们属于一位1981年出生的女性
They belong to a woman, born in 1981,
1998年因殴打被捕 也就是我们采集她指纹的时候
arrested for assault in 1998, which is when we took her prints.
- 她叫什么名字 - 有 丽斯贝丝·萨兰德
- Does she have a name? - Yes, Lisbeth Salander.
抱歉 但我找不到霍格·帕姆格伦有养女的记录
Sorry, but I can find no record that Holger Palmgren had a foster daughter.
但他知道 他从13岁起一直照顾我 直到他中风
But he does. He took care of me from the age of 13 until his stroke.
我是他最亲近的亲戚
I'm the closest relative he has.
他会好起来吗
Will he be OK?
我将坦率地对你说
I'll be frank with you.
他今晚可能脑出血 也可能活20年
He could have a brain haemorrhage tonight or he could live for 20 years.
老实说我也不知道
I honestly don't know.
没有专科护理吗
Isn't there any specialist care?
恐怕我们是专科医生
I'm afraid we are the specialist care.
我希望我们有更好的资源 不必进行这些削减
I wish we had better resources and didn't have to make these cuts.
如果你不用担心裁员 你会为他做什么
If you didn't have to worry about cuts, what would you do for him?
好吧
Well...
理想的情况是 有一位可以全职与他一起工作的私人教练
Ideally, a personal trainer that could work with him full time.
- 聘用一名员工 - 当然
- Employ one. - Sure.
我会付钱的 为霍尔格聘请一名私人教练
I'll pay. Take on a personal trainer for Holger.
- 你知道要花多少钱吗 - 不知道
- Have you any idea of the cost? - NO.
我找到了枪的主人 一个比约曼人
I tracked down the gun's owner, one Bjurman.
他不在家 也不在办公室
He wasn't at home or in his office.
一位同事说 他两年前生病了 几乎停止了工作
A colleague said he fell sick two years ago and practically stopped working.
我已经让索尼娅负责了 索尼娅
I've put Sonja onto it. Sonja?
比约曼现年56岁 无犯罪记录
Bjurman is 56, no criminal record.
他主要是一名商业律师 但我相信我们会得到更多关于他的信息
He's mainly a business lawyer, but I'm sure we'll get more on him.
对不起我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
我被困在监护机构了
I got stuck at the Guardianship Agency.
监护机构
Guardianship Agency?
莉斯贝丝·萨兰德看起来很不安 她在法律上被宣布为无行为能力
Lisbeth Salander seems pretty disturbed. She was declared legally incompetent.
猜猜她的监护人是谁
And guess who her guardian is?
拥有枪支的律师比约曼用来杀害那对夫妇
Bjurman, the lawyer who owns the gun used to kill that couple.
在学校制造麻烦 在精神病院度过时间
A troublemaker at school, spent time in mental institutions,
涉嫌卖淫 并有长期的暴力行为历史
suspected of prostitution, and has a long history of violent behaviour.
我们有没有找到那对被谋杀夫妇的线索
Do we have a link to the murdered couple?
还没
Not yet.
据税务局称 她受雇于米尔顿证券公司
According to the tax office, she's been employed at Milton Security.
她为他们做了什么 - 我不知道干干净净的 也许
- What did she do for them? - I don't know. Cleaned, maybe?
- 我们有地址吗 - 伦达格坦 在斯德哥尔摩
- Do we have an address? - Lundagatan, here in Stockholm.
萨兰德在伦达格坦吗
Was Salander at Lundagatan?
- 不 我们在等后援 - 这需要多长时间
- No, we're waiting for backup. - How long will that take?
我不知道 大概五到十分钟吧
I don't know. Five to ten minutes maybe.
我明白了
I see.
为什么要花这么长时间呢
wWwhy should it take so bloody long?
好了
Done.
- 事情就是这样 给我打电话 - 我们做完了我会打电话给你的
- That's just how it is. Call me later. - I'll call you when we're done.
- 那么 再见 - 当然 再见
- Bye, then. - Sure. Bye.
天哪 这些天的妓女
Christ, the whores these days.
他们变得越来越丑 你能去接她吗
They get uglier and uglier. Would you pick her up?
一定有比这更简单的方法
There's got to be an easier way than this.
你什么意思
wWwhat do you mean?
我们不需要冲锋队把所有的卑鄙小人都抓起来
We don't need the storm troops to pick up every last lowlife.
她个子很小 五英尺高 六英石
She's tiny, five feet tall and six stone.
- 我们进去了 但没人在这里 - 好的 明白了
- We're in, but no one's here. - OK, understood.
闻起来像是刚画好的
Smells freshly painted.
厨房装修得怎么样了
How's the kitchen renovation going?
太贵了 而且没完没了
It's expensive, and it never fucking ends.
- 嘿 法斯特 - 是的
- Hey, Faste. - Yes.
为什么门上的铭牌上写着Salander - Wu
why did the nameplate on the door say Salander - Wu?
我没有头绪
I have no idea.
伙计 有人玩得很开心
Man, someone's been having fun!
我不认为萨兰德住在这里
I don't think Salander lives here.
这些邮件都是寄给米莉安·吴的
The mail is all addressed to Miriam Wu.
处方药 也开给了米里亚姆·吴
Prescription drugs, also made out to Miriam Wu.
这里没有萨兰德的任何东西
There's nothing of Salander's here.
我是尼尔斯·埃里克·比约曼 请留言
You have reached Nils Erik Bjurman. Please leave a message.
你好?
Hello?
我给了她一份工作 直到18个月前
I gave her work until about 18 months ago.
- 什么样的工作 - 研究 个人案例研究
- What kind of work? - Research, personal case studies.
- 她是个体户 - 等一下
- She's self - employed. - Hold on.
我心目中的莉斯贝丝·萨兰德没有学校成绩
The Lisbeth Salander I'm thinking of lacks school grades.
她的论文中没有说她可以做一项复杂的工作
Nothing in her papers says she could do a complex job.
纸是一回事 人是另一回事
Papers are one thing, people are another.
- 听起来你很尊重她 - 我尊重她的能力
- Sounds like you have respect for her. - I respect her competence.
你知道我们在哪里能找到她吗
Do you know where we can find her?
我想知道她的嫌疑是什么
I'd like to know what she's suspected of.
- 她有没有访客 - 没有她在家工作
- Did she ever have any visitors here? - No. She worked from home.
她只是偶尔见一下客户
She only met clients occasionally.
- 尽管 - 什么
- Although... - What?
一年前 她为一名记者工作 这名记者不时地向她打招呼
She worked for a journalist a year ago who's asked after her now and then.
- 记者 - Mikael Blomkvist
- A journalist? - Mikael Blomkvist.
打扰了 我得接个电话
Excuse me. I have to get this.
是的 莫迪格 怎么了
Yes, Modig, what's up?
也从那个角度拿一些 这样我们就可以看到一切
Get some from that angle, too, so that we can see everything.
她在里面
She's in there.
谢谢 我真想喝杯咖啡
Thanks. I was dying for some coffee.
- 找到什么了吗 - 除了比约曼 还有一个空枪盒
- Found anything? - Apart from Bjurman, an empty gun case.
一些指纹和装满关于萨兰德的评估报告的活页夹
Some prints and a binder full of evaluation reports about Salander.
他向监护机构提交的报告
His reports to the Guardianship Agency.
根据那些报道 萨兰德是个天使
And according to those reports, Salander's an angel.
我搞不懂她
can't figure her out.
法斯特说她有精神病 没受过教育
Faste says she's psychopathic, uneducated.
阿曼斯基说 她是一名称职的研究员
Armansky says she's a competent researcher.
我们把他翻过来了 有些东西你应该看看
We turned him over. There's something you should see.
“我是一头虐待狂的猪 还是个强奸犯 ”
"] am a sadistic pig and a rapist."
- 你觉得呢 - 这是一个很好的谋杀动机
- What do you think? - It's a fine motive for murder.
这太荒谬了 丽斯贝丝·萨兰德和达格和米娅没有任何关系
It's ridiculous. Lisbeth Salander had nothing to do with Dag and Mia.
我知道你一年前雇她做了一些研究
I understand that you employed her to do some research a year ago.
- 你觉得她是个好研究员吗 - 是的最好的
- Did you find her a good researcher? - Yes. The best.
- 那她的社交障碍呢 - 残障
- What about her social handicap? - Handicap?
她的精神问题 监护权
Her mental problems, the guardianship.
- 监护 - 你和阿曼斯基怎么了
- Guardianship? - What is it with you and Armansky?
她曾住过精神病院 在法律上不称职 有暴力记录
She's been in a mental hospital, is legally incompetent and has a record of violence.
她从小就有麻烦了
She's been in trouble since she was little.
现在她被怀疑犯有三重谋杀罪
And now she's suspected of a triple murder.
而你和阿曼斯基说话就像她是公主一样
And you and Armansky talk as if she was a princess.
三重谋杀
Triple murder?
三起谋杀案嫌疑人
SUSPECT IN TRIPLE MURDER
因双重谋杀罪被通缉
WANTED FOR DOUBLE MURDER
因谋杀罪被通缉
WANTED FOR MURDER
明星记者布隆维斯特发现被谋杀的夫妇
MURDERED COUPLE FOUND BY STAR REPORTER BLOMKVIST
Peter Teleborian 你甚至更挑剔 说这是可耻的
Peter Teleborian, you're even more critical and say it's scandalous
她没有得到她需要的治疗
that she didn't receive the treatment she needed.
我不想讨论个别病人
I prefer not to discuss individual patients.
但我确实认为 某些复杂的案件需要专科医生的护理
But I do believe that certain complex cases require specialist care.
不幸的是 已经有三人丧生
And it's unfortunate that three lives have been lost
由于精神科护理部门的削减
as a result of cutbacks in the psychiatric care sector.
所以她应该被关起来
S0 she should have been locked up?
一些病人在机构里的生活比在社会上普遍的生活要好
Some patients are better off in institutions than at large in society.
谢谢 庞图斯·莱文和彼得·泰尔博里安
Thank you, Pontus Levin and Peter Teleborian,
乌普萨拉郊外圣斯特凡儿童精神病学诊所的顾问
consultant at St Stefan's Child Psychiatry Clinic outside Uppsala,
那个被通缉的女人曾经在那里接受治疗
where the wanted woman was once treated.
今天又发现一名男子被谋杀
Another man was found murdered today.
一名56岁的律师 以社会工作闻名 显然是在斯德哥尔摩的家中被枪杀
A 56 - year - old lawyer, well known for his social work, was apparently shot in his Stockholm home.
警方认为这三起凶杀案是有关联的
The police believe the three homicides are connected.
其中一名受害者达格·斯文森曾为《千年》杂志工作
One ofthe victims, Dag Svensson, worked for Millennium magazine,
其执行主编是Mikael Blomkvist
whose executive editor is Mikael Blomkvist.
斯文森正要在千禧年报上发表一篇关于计算机安全和黑客的文章
Svensson was about to publish an article in Millennium about computer security and hacking.
这对他的家人、他的同事和所有瑞典记者来说都是一个巨大的损失
It's a huge loss for his family, for his colleagues and for all Swedish journalists.
我们的社会遭到了残酷的攻击
Our society has been brutally attacked.
- 你为什么这么说 - 因为这是真的
- Why did you say that? - Because it's true.
DAG计划稍后写一篇关于信息安全的文章
Dag was planning to write an article about information security later on.
我也想在警方之前找到某个人
I also want to reach a certain person before the police does.
我知道利斯贝丝会读我写的每一本书 不管她在哪里
I know Lisbeth reads everything I write, no matter where she is.
她对计算机安全问题非常感兴趣
She's extremely interested in computer security matters.
如果我说对了 也许她会想联系我
If I say the right things, maybe she!ll feel like contacting me.
- 你不怀疑吗 - 不怀疑什么
- You have no doubts? - About what?
如果你问我利斯贝思是否有能力杀人 答案是肯定的
If you asked me if Lisbeth was capable of murder, the answer would be yes.
她很暴力 我亲眼目睹了她的行动
She's violent. I've seen her in action.
- 她救你的时候 - 不是
- When she saved you? - NO.
- 不 什么 - 不 丽斯贝丝没有杀任何人
- No, what? - No, Lisbeth didn't kill anyone.
那是达格的手机
That's Dag's phone.
我去拿吧
I'll get that.
- Indigo市场研究公司 - 我叫贡纳·比约克
- Indigo Marketing Research. - My name's Gunnar Björck.
我刚从你那里收到一份很有意思的工作
I just received a very interesting offer from you.
将文件复制到WASP
COPYING FILES TO WASP
- 我敢肯定是利斯贝丝 - 她在找什么文件
- I'rm Sure it was Lisbeth. - What documents was she after?
可能是我和达格·斯文森的电子邮件 或者他的研究材料
Probably my emails with Dag Svensson, or his research material.
你能追踪到她吗 - 不能她不是那样工作的
- Can you trace her? - No. She doesn't work that way.
我想她有理由继续躲起来
I guess she's got reason to stay in hiding.
- 所以你也认为她有罪 - 我什么都不会说的
- S0 you think she's guilty too? - I'm not saying anything.
我知道她什么都没做
I know she didn't do anything.
至少这次不会
Not this time, at least.
我们把一切都颠覆了 但这一切都属于米里亚姆·吴
wWe've turned everything upside down, but it all belongs to Miriam Wu.
我们对她了解多少
wWhat do we know about her?
没有定罪 一个臭名昭著的女同性恋者 在节目中表演 假装学习社会学
No convictions, a notorious lesbian who performs in shows and pretends to study sociology.
她还在镇上共同拥有一家色情商店：多米诺时尚
She also co - owns a porn shop in town: Domino Fashion.
- 色情商店 多米诺时尚 - 他们卖手铐和妓女服装
- Porn shop? Domino Fashion? - They sell handcuffs and whore - wear.
这不是色情商店 他们把衣服卖给喜欢性感内衣的人
It's not a porn shop. They sell clothes to people who like racy underwear.
你在那里购物吗
Do you shop there?
- 所以没有关于这个米里亚姆·吴的线索 - 没有
- Soö no leads on this Miriam Wu? - No.
如果她是同性恋 我们能得出她和萨兰德是情侣的结论吗
If she's a lesbian, can we conclude that she and Salander are a couple?
我们认为是这样 我们在一些手铐上发现了萨兰德的指纹
We think so. We found Salander's prints on some handocuffs.
公寓里到处都是性玩具
The flat was littered with sex toys.
我们收到的另一个线报是萨兰德和吴
Another tip - off that we've received is that Salander and Wu
曾经和一个叫邪恶手指的女孩团体混在一起
once hung around with a girl group called Evil Fingers.
- 那是什么 - 似乎是某种神秘的东西
- What's that? - Seems to be something occult.
- 就连我都听说过邪恶的手指 - 你听说过吗
- Even I've heard of Evil Fingers! - Have you?
90年代末的一支摇滚乐队
A rock band at the end of the '90s.
- 他们不是超级明星 但是 - 他们都是女同性恋撒旦教徒
- They weren't superstars, but... - They're all lesbian Satanists.
天啊 你对女人的看法来自侏罗纪公园
Jesus, your view of women is from Jurassic Park.
那就是普通的白色瓷砖
Normal white tiles, then.
为什么不行
why not?
意大利菜 正确的
Italian? Right.
那么 这要花多少钱呢
wWhat does that cost, then?
这是不包括增值税还是包括增值税
Is that excluding or including VAT?
我明白了 不 不 我当然希望它看起来漂亮 好的 宝贝
I see. No, no, of course I want it to look nice. Yes, baby.
把我放开!
Let go of me!
那我们就选意大利菜吧
We'll go with the Italian, then.
我是因为什么事被捕的吗
Am I arrested for something?
- 上午11：10采访Miriam Wu - 我能走了吗
- Interview with Miriam Wu, 11:10am. - Can I go?
从技术上讲 是的
Technically, yes.
- 不严格来说呢 - 我们只是想要一些信息
- And untechnically? - We just want some information.
- 你能告诉我们你去过哪里吗 - 告诉我为什么我先来这里
- Can you tell us where you've been? - Tell me why I'm here first.
我回到家 发现门被强行封锁了
I get home, find the door forced and cordoned off,
然后这个自以为是的男人毫无解释地把我拉到这里
and then this self - righteous male drags me here without explanation.
你不喜欢男人吗
Don't you like males?
你没看过最近的报纸吗
Haven't you read the papers recently?
我刚从巴黎回来 在那里我看望了我的父母
I've just come back from Paris where I visited my parents.
你没看过任何瑞典新闻吗
And you haven't seen any Swedish news?
我刚从夜班火车回到家 然后就是这个
I'd just got home from the night train, and then this.
她在哪 米里亚姆
Where is she, Miriam?
- 什么 - 你们住在一起
- What the...? - You live together.
不 我们没有 她刚把她的公寓给了我
No, we don't. She's just given me her flat.
- 你接管了她的公寓 - S 利斯贝丝在哪里
- You've taken over her flat? - Söo where's Lisbeth?
- 我不知道 - 你想让我们相信你吗
- I don't know. - Do you want us to believe you?
让我们从她是如何养活自己开始的
Let's start with how she's supporting herself.
- 我不知道 - 你不知道
- I don't know. - You don't know.
我们并不是以那种方式相互了解的
We don't know each other in that way.
- 她在卖淫吗 - 当然不是你为什么这么问
- Is she prostituting herself? - Of course not. Why do you ask that?
- 但你承认认识莉斯贝丝 - 是的
- But you admit to knowing Lisbeth? - Yes.
你和她上床了吗
Do you have sex with her?
嘿 如果我和她上床 那不关你的事
Hey, If I have sex with her that's none of your business!
公寓里堆满了性玩具
The flat was full of sex toys.
除了她 你还会用那个假阴茎操别人吗
Do you fuck other people than her with that dildo?
所以你找到了那个假阴茎 令人兴奋 那么你在幻想什么呢
S0 you found the dildo. Exciting. So what are you fantasising about?
- 或者你把它推到什么地方了 - 闭嘴 回答问题
- Or have you shoved it somewhere? - Shut up and answer the question.
你问我是不是用假阴茎操莉斯贝丝 我说这不关你的事
You ask if I fuck Lisbeth with a dildo, and I say its none of your business!
暂停对吴健仪的采访 上午11：12
Suspending interview with Miriam Wu, 11:12am.
法斯特 我能跟你说句话吗
Faste, can I have a word?
为什么
How come...
祝好运
Good luck.
- 比约克在这里 - 你好 是我 来自Indigo
- Björck here. - Hello, it's me, from Indigo.
太棒了 你得到怎么来这里的指示了吗
Great. Did you get instructions on how to get here?
- 当然 没问题 - 那彩票和电话呢
- Sure, no problem. - What about the lottery and the phone?
你仍然是被选中的20人之一
You are still one of the chosen 20.
- 你好 贡纳·比约克
- Hello. - Gunnar Björck?
- 没错 你找到了 - 没问题
- That's right. You found it? - No problem.
好的 进来
OK. Come in.
我们见过吗 - 没有
- Have we met? - No.
不知何故 你看起来很眼熟
You look familiar somehow.
你可能在报纸上见过我
You might have seen me in the papers.
好的 你叫什么名字来着
OK. What was your name again?
米克尔·布隆维斯特 我是《千年》杂志的记者
Mikael Blomkvist. I'm a journalist for Millennium magazine.
千禧年
Millennium?
我不知道你在做市场调查
I had no idea you did marketing research.
嗯 有时候我们会这样做
Well, occasionally we do.
我想让你看这三幅画 然后告诉我你最喜欢哪一种型号
I'd like you to look at these three pictures and then tell me which model you like the best.
好的
Sure.
第一个是利迪亚·科莫罗娃 她才16岁
The first is Lidia Komorova. She's 16.
她来自白俄罗斯的明斯克
And she's from Minsk, Belarus.
然后是明素勋
Then there's Myang So Hun.
她今年25岁 比我大一点
She's 25, a little bit older.
但这并没有表现出来
But it doesn't show.
她的昵称是Jo - Jo 她来自泰国
Her nickname is Jo - Jo, and she's from Thailand.
然后是西尔维娅 她的真名是叶琳娜·巴拉索娃
Then there's Silvia, whose real name is Yelena Barasova.
她今年19岁 来自塔林
She's 19, and she's from Tallinn.
你从这三个女人那里买了性爱
You bought sex from all three of these women.
所以我想知道 很简单 你最喜欢哪一个
S0 I was wondering, quite simply, which one did you like the best.
- 这是开玩笑吗 - 不是
- Is this a joke? - NO.
我们的记者达格·斯文森找到了你利用这些女性进行性交易的证据
Our reporter, Dag Svensson, found proof that you used these women for sexual purposes.
- 他联系过你吗 - 谁
- Did he ever contact you? - Who?
达格·斯文森
Dag Svensson.
我从来没听说过他
I've never heard of him.
- 我要你离开 - 这可能是真的
- I want you to leave. - That could be true.
他可能在被枪击前没有时间和你对质
He probably didn't have time to confront you before he was shot.
你认识比约曼 那个律师吗
Do you know Bjurman, the lawyer?
你想要什么
what do you want?
我们给那些买了性爱的男人
Wer're giving the men who bought sex
在我们出版我们的人口贩运特刊之前有机会回应
a chance to respond before we publish our special trafficking issue.
你意识到如果你发表这篇文章 我的生活将被毁掉吗
Do you realise that my life will be destroyed if you publish this?
是
Yes.
来吧 妈妈 你说什么呢
Come on, Mum. what are you talking about?
听着 这是他妈的警察干的 不 是警察
Listen, the fucking cops did this! No, the police.
这地方真是一团糟 我不知道 她走了 消失了
The place is a mess! I don't know. She's gone, vanished.
坚持住 有人在敲门
Hang on. There's someone at the door.
你好 米里亚姆 托尼·斯卡拉 记者 你的女朋友是谋杀案嫌疑人
Hello, Miriam. Tony Scala, reporter. Your girlfriend is a murder suspect.
你知道莉斯贝丝·萨兰德现在在哪里吗
Do you know where Lisbeth Salander is right now?
米里亚姆 你得和媒体谈谈 我可以帮你
Miriam. You've got to talk to the press, and I can help you.
去死吧 你这个混蛋
Go to hell, you bastard!
你回来的时候我会掐死你的 丽斯贝丝
I'll strangle you when you get back, Lisbeth.
您还在吗 那是个该死的记者 不 我告诉过你 她走了
Are you still there? It was a bloody reporter. No, I told you, she's gone!
伊琳娜的身体在这里被发现
IRINA'S BODY FOUND HERE
达格·斯文森的研究文案
DAG SVENSSON'S RESEARCH COPY
对峙 - 投注者
CONFRONTATIONS - PUNTERS
伊利纳族：俄罗斯
IRINA NATIONALITY: RUSSIA
经常访问伊利纳Check Anton=Zala
FREQUENT VISITS TO IRINA CHECK ANTON = ZALA
我在工作呢 你想要什么
I'm working. What do you want?
你刚才抬头看的这个扎拉琴科是谁
Who's this Zalachenko yOou just looked up?
- 不关你的事 - 但是 嘿……你为什么要开枪打他们
- None of your business. - But, hey... why did you shoot them?
- 嘿 怎么了 - 我需要你的帮助
- Hey, what happened? - I need your help.
我在找93年警方关于我的机密文件
I'm after a confidential police file on me from '93.
我找不到了 - 它不会在1993年被数字化
- I cantt find it. - It wouldn't be digitalised in 1993.
那是很久以前的事了
It's a long time ago.
你那时多大 12岁
How old were you then, 12?
- 你能试着找到它吗 我会付你钱的 - 好的
- Can you try to find it? I'll pay you. - OK.
如果您还需要什么 请通过Hotmail联系我
Contact me on Hotmail if you need anything else.
- 你知道你是个反社会的人 对吗 - 你知道你是完全正常的 对吗
- You know you're a sociopath, right? - You know yourre totally normal, right?
这就对了
There you go.
那里 欢迎回来
There. Welcome back.
女同性恋撒旦的帮派LED
GANG LED BY LESBIAN SATANIST
- 米里亚姆·吴 - 是的
- Miriam Wu? - Yes.
我是Mikael Blomkvist
Mikael Blomkvist here.
- 我们见过一面 然后 - 滚开 你这个该死的记者
- We met once and... - Fuck off, you fucking journalist!
他妈的 他妈的 他妈的
Shit. Shit. Shit.
这就是你想坐的位置吗
So this is were you like to sit?
嗨
Hi.
谢谢你给我回电话
Thanks for returning my call.
你的调查就像筛子一样泄露了
Your investigation is leaking like a sieve.
“女同性恋撒旦帮派头目 ”太棒了
"Lesbian Satanist gang leader." whoopee.
我能私下跟你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you off the record?
我其实并不是为小报工作
I don't actually work for the tabloids.
你知道我的意思 现在你在做自己的调查
You know what I mean. And now you're doing your own investigations.
一份双份浓缩咖啡
One double espresso.
- 你为什么认为她是无辜的 - 她没有理由杀他们
- Why do you think she's innocent? - She had no reason to kill them.
尤其是米娅 她当时正在揭露一个人口贩运团伙
Especially not Mia, who was exposing a trafficking ring.
利斯贝思会同意的 她鄙视憎恨女人的男人
Lisbeth would approve. She despises men who hate women.
我们有证据表明利斯贝思当时在谋杀现场
We have evidence that Lisbeth was at the murder scene.
- 你有指纹吗 - 她被绑在枪上了
- Have you got fingerprints? - She's been tied to the gun.
这并不意味着她开枪打死了他们
That doesn't mean she shot them.
- 比约曼呢 - 答案就在达格的材料里
- What about Bjurman? - The answer's in Dag's material.
这是警方的事
This is a police matter.
- 跳过疯狂的理论 - 我没有任何理论
- Skip the crazy theories. - I don't have any theories.
我坚持认为莉斯贝丝没有杀达格和米娅
I maintain that Lisbeth didn't kill Dag and Mia.
我会找到证据的 我会找到凶手的
I will find evidence. I will find the killer.
我会写一篇警察会觉得非常不舒服的文章
And I will write an article that the police will find damn uncomfortable.
我得回去了 我有个午餐会
I'd better get back. I have a lunch meeting.
- 你和她有联系吗 - 谁
- Have you been in touch with her? - Who?
我能指的是谁
who could I possibly mean?
一位老朋友今早打来电话
An old friend called this morning...
她也不相信是利斯贝丝·萨兰德干的
...who doesn't believe Lisbeth Salander did it either.
谁?
who?
天哪 全歪了 他妈的
My God, it's all crooked. Shit.
埃里卡
Erika!
你们两个见面聊聊会更好
It'd be better for the two of you to meet and talk.
刺拳 保罗 去吧 刺拳
Jab, Paolo! Go on! Jab!
动动你的脚 步法 移动!
Move your feet! Footwork! Move!
赶快!别放弃!
Come on! Don't give up!
- 你怎么认识利斯贝丝的 - 打拳击 从她17岁起
- How do you know Lisbeth? - Through boxing, since she was 17.
- 就像在同一个重量级别 - 她真的是个拳击手 也很活泼
- Like in the same weight class? - She really is a boxer. Feisty too.
她有麻烦了 不是吗
She's in trouble, isn't she?
她浑身都是屎 我需要你的帮助 保罗
She's in deep shit. I need your help, Paolo.
我要找她的一个朋友 米里亚姆·吴
I need to find a friend of hers, Miriam Wu.
你听说过她吗 - 我认识她一位顽强的拳击手
- You've heard of her? - I know her. A tough kick - boxer.
- 她不会和记者交谈 - 我能理解为什么
- She wontt talk to journalists. - I can understand why.
我想如果你 作为一名拳击手 和她认识的人 联系她
I figured that if you, being a boxer, and one she knows, contacted her...
那我们就有可能找到莉斯贝丝了
Then we could possibly find Lisbeth?
来吧 起来
Come on, get up.
赶快 起床
Come on. Get up.
起立
Stand up.
我要问你几个问题 回答他们 我就让你活着
I'm going to ask you some questions. Answer them, and I'll let you live.
如果你拒绝 我会再次电击你 就像我在外面做的那样 100,000伏
If you refuse, I'll zap you again, just like I did outside. 100,000 volts.
如果你撒谎 或者躲躲闪闪 我也会杀了你
If you lie, or are evasive, I'll zap you, too.
你的肌肉会停止工作 你最终会勒死自己：
Your muscles will stop working and you'll end up strangling yourself:
我就走了 清楚了吗
And I'll just leave. Is that clear?
我不想死
I don't want to die.
我的错 我忘了告诉你 除非我说 否则你不能说话
My bad. I forgot to tell you that you can't speak unless I say so.
- 这是你女儿吗 - 是的 她随时都会来
- Is this your daughter? - Yes, she'll be here any second.
你又犯规了
You broke the rules again.
- 你想死吗 - 不想
- Do you want to die? - NO.
你是个虐待狂的猪还是个强奸犯
You are a sadistic pig and a rapist.
不是你吗?
Aren't you?
扎拉是谁
who's Zala?
我不知道
I don't know.
到目前为止 你做得很好 别搞砸了
You've done well so far. Don't blow it.
我不知道 你开枪打死的那个记者也问了我同样的问题
I don't know. The journalist you shot asked me the same thing.
如果我知道 我发誓我会告诉你的
If I knew, I swear I'd tell you.
我曾经和一个自称扎拉的人在电话里聊过
I once spoke to a man on the phone who called himself Zala.
为什么
why?
他让我从塔林带一车安非他明过来
He told me to bring in a carload of amphetamines from Tallinn.
我不想这么做 后来他们来到这里 说现在打退堂鼓已经太晚了
I didn't want to. Later they came here and said that it was too late to back out.
- 他们强迫我去 - 致
- They forced me to go to... - To?
某种仓库
Some kind of warehouse.
我看到这个人躺在地上 被打成肉酱
I saw this guy on the floor, beaten to a pulp.
- 他就在那里 - 谁 扎拉
- And he was there. - Who? Zala?
不 是这个金发混蛋 全是肌肉
No, this blond bastard. All muscle.
在那之前我见过他一次 真他妈可怕
I'd seen him once before that. Fucking scary.
他叫什么名字 - 我不知道
- What's his name? - I don't know.
- 接下来发生了什么 - 他们说那家伙告密了
- What happened next? - They said the guy had squealed.
那个金发男人把他放在我前面的椅子上
The blond guy set him down on a chair in front of me.
然后他把手搭在那家伙的脖子上
And he put his hands around the guy's neck.
我听到他的脖子断了
I heard his neck snap.
他死了 就在我眼前
He died, right before my eyes!
然后呢 - 然后他抓住了我的脖子
- And? - Then he grabbed me by the neck.
Magge把电话放在我耳边 因为Zala有个口信要给我
Magge held a phone to my ear, because Zala had a message for me.
那么他说了什么 这个扎拉
So what did he say... this Zala?
照我说的做
To do as I was told.
好像我他妈的别无选择
Like I had a fucking choice!
你好?
Hello?
见鬼 怎么回事
wWhat the hell?
硬盘
The hard drive?
一大堆人 你自己读吧
The lot. Read for yourself.
- 这是什么 - 扣押令
- So what's this? - The seizure warrant.
是布布兰斯基 他生气是因为我没能帮上忙
It's Bublanski. He's pissed because I'm not being more helpful.
我们已经有了所有的副本 所以让我们在任何其他事情发生之前把这一期拿出来
We've got copies of everything, so let's get this issue out before anything else happens.
你好?
Hello?
电池电量不足
LOW BATTERY
他妈的!
Shit!
米克 你想让我去看看冈纳·比约克
Micke, you wanted me to check up on Gunnar Björck.
比约曼的名字出现了
Bjurman's name came up.
比约曼在国家警察局工作 也就是安全部门
Bjurman worked for the National Police Board, the security department.
- 什么 什么时候 - 从1976年到1978年
- What? When? - From 1976 to 1978.
- 比约克在那里的时候 - 我靠
- When Björck was there. - Holy shit.
- 她在哪里 - 谁
- Where is she? - Who?
- 莉斯贝丝·萨兰德 - 我不知道
- Lisbeth Salander. - I don't know!
最后一次机会 在我打开这个之前
One last chance... before I turn this on.
我没有杀达格和米娅 如果你想帮我就去找扎拉
I didn't kill Dag and Mia. Find Zala if you want to help me.